别试了。你知道这不可能。
Quit trying. You know it's impossible.
我们唯一可能是毫无可能。
Only chance we've got is no chance at all.
我知道这不可能做到。
I know it can't be done.
我真的很高兴你不知道!
I'm just glad that you didn't know it!
我希望你意识到你袖手旁观。
I hope you realize you did nothing to help the situation.
来，对付这个。
Here, work on these.
我会像老鼠一样安静。
I'll be quiet as a mouse.
这需要团队合作，蒂莎。
It takes teamwork, Tisa.
好吗?
OK?
准备,开始!
Ready, go!
我有个主意，如果我们能倒转极性
I've got an idea, that if we can reverse the polarity
解开手铐，我们离自由的一步之遥
on these cuffs, the only thing standing between us and freedom
是偷一艘飞船。
is stealing a starship.
哦,当然。
Oh, sure.
这就是全部吗?
Is that all?
想想看，我还发愁出去呢。
And to think I was worried there for a second.
如果我们能用链子把牢锁短路的话
If we could short circuit the lock on the cell with a chain--
是的，但是我们戴着链子。
Yeah, but we're wearing the chains.
小小的电击不会伤害任何人。
A little shock never hurt anyone.
给我助推一下。
Give me a boost step.
准备?
Ready?
1、2、3 !
1, 2, 3!
再高几英寸。
Just a few more inches.
我就要够到了。
I almost got it.
再高一点。
Go over a little bit.
碰到了!
Got it!
你没事吧?
TISA: Are you all right?
也许有点烤熟了。
A little well done, perhaps.
嘿，我们出去!
Hey, we're out of here!
你迟到了。
You're late.
有什么稀奇的?
What else is new?
你看到那两个隔离监禁的吗?
Did you see those two they threw in solitary today?
还没有。
Not yet.
我愿意用一年的工资换里面爽10分钟。
I'd give a year's pay for 10 minutes in there.
哦!
Oh!
Uh!
噢。呃。
Ow. Uh.
重抓黄瓜的感觉真好。
Feels good to be back in the saddle again.
我可以说些粗话，但我不会说。
I could say something rude, but I won't.
这艘船的航程是多少?
What kind of range does this ship got?
乞丐没法选择。
Beggars can't be choosers.
有，我们可能要选择被遗忘的航线。
Yeah, we could be choosing a course to oblivion.
至少这是我们的选择。
At least it's our choice.
如果你无所谓去哪的话
Well, if it's all the same to you,
我宁愿不要俗话道半路没电了。
I'd rather not run out of power between worlds, as they say.
看看这个。
Well, look at this.
导航系统――这不是一艘破烂船
Netaglide-- this isn't a shabby-ass derelict
我们在开。
we're driving.
我们用原子感应来烧烤。
We're cooking with atomic induction.
好了，大厨，我们快飞吧，在太烫手之前。
OK, chef, let's take off before things get too hot.
别急着脱内裤，妹妹。
Keep your pants on, sister.
我得先破解弹射密码，
I've got to unscramble the launch code first,
还有打开逃生口。
and open the escape hatch.
我乐意把这艘母舰的墙顶个洞
I'd love to punch a hole through the wall of this mothership
只要我是公的，但我不确定我们有没有
if I could, but I'm not sure if we've
足够的能量起跑。
got enough of a running start.
我们需要戴特殊的手套来使用这台电脑。
We need a special glove to access this computer.
-试试手套箱。-你真可爱。
- Try the glove compartment. - Oh, you're cute.
再给神奇手指一秒钟，
Just give these magic fingers another second,
我要给这只笨狗下指令。
and I'll have this puppy programmed.
- 你真聪明。- 明得耀眼。
- You're brilliant. - Dazzling.
人们必须戴太阳镜。
People have to wear sunglasses.
好了。应该可以了。
There. That should do the trick.
点火装置在哪里?
Well, where's the ignition?
哦，别又开始了。
Oh, don't start that again.
接下来你会想让我跳下去
Next thing you're going to want me to get out and jump
启动它。
start it.
- 到底是什么声音? - 猜。
- What the hell is that? - Guess.
要是我们让两个奴隶跑了，我们会被降级。
We let a couple slaves escape, we're going to be busted.
引擎已热。
Engine's hot.
防御驱力已开。
Defense drive engaged.
我们上路。
We're on our way.
我们走。
Let's go.
检查扫描装置。
Check the scanners.
让我们看看我们到底有多自由。
Let's find out just how free we are.
附近有东西吗?
Anything nearby?
外面有点黑。
It's kind of dark out there.
到底有东西吗?
Anything at all?
在我看来，我们在漫游鬼城。
Looks to me like we're cruising the town of nowhere.
- 这只是一艘救生艇。- 是的。
- This is only a lifeboat. - Yeah.
我们的装备真没法星系跳跃。
We're not exactly equipped to go galaxy hopping.
我们选择的弃船时机真好。
We picked a fine time to jump ship.
我捡拾到信号，离这里不远
I'm picking up something, not far from here--
信标。
beacon.
这里有?
Out here?
我们来看看。
Let's check it out.
它来自那个小行星。
TISA: It's coming from that small planetoid.
你知道吗，这有点蹊跷。
You know, there's something odd about this.
这个信号不仅仅是安全航道信标。
That signal isn't just a safe channel beacon.
光束正在传送天文导航着陆
That beam's transmitting astro-navigational landing
坐标。
coordinates.
我们在这里找到一块大得可以降落的岩石就算幸运
We'd be lucky to find a rock out here big enough to set down
你还质疑宜居世界的邀请
on, and you're questioning an invitation to a habitable world
质疑着陆跑道?
with a landing strip?
我就把定向网格光束
I'll lock the beam of the directional grid
锁定入快速引导系统。
into the hyperdrive system.
不对劲!
Something's wrong!
我们的轨道下降速度是不是有点快?
TISA: Aren't we dipping the orbit a bit fast?
踩下刹车!
Hit the brakes!
切断牵引光束。
Cut the tractor beam.
反推器不点火。
Retros aren't firing.
我们没有减速!
We're not slowing down!
驾船脱离。
Disengage [INAUDIBLE].
它被锁定在某种自动驾驶上!
It's locked in some kind of autopilot!
什么也不工作了。
Nothing's functioning.
光束正在盖过我们的控制。
The beam is overriding our controls.
引擎不反转。
Engines won't reverse.
我无法拉起来!
I can't pull it out!
我们在下坠!
We're going down!
我们别无选择。
We've got no choice.
我们必须跳伞。
We're going to have to jump for it.
机会渺茫。
Slim chance.
比没有机会强。
Better than none.
我们就乘坐火箭尽可能接近地面
We'll ride this rocket as close as we can, then
然后跳伞，希望有好结果。
bail out and hope for the best.
说得对，不是吗?
TISA: This is it, isn't it?
也许成功了呢。
You never know.
下面有大气层。
There is an atmosphere down there.
对，但我们能呼吸吗?
Yeah, but can we breathe it?
我们很快就会知道了。
We'll soon find out.
这真不是我所希望的结果。
This wasn't exactly the way I hoped things would turn out.
有人在这里吗?
Is anybody here?
有人在家吗?
is there anybody home?
我不是想闯入。
I'm not trying to break in.
我的飞船在岛的远端坠入大海。
My ship crashed into the sea on the far side of the island.
恐怕我是唯一的幸存者。
I'm afraid I'm the only survivor.
你能听懂我的语言吗?
Can you understand my language?
你编程了说话吗?
Are you programmed to speak?
他从来不跟别人说话，除非我指示他。
ZED: He never talks to others, unless I instruct him to.
然而，他听得懂每一个字。
However, he understood every word.
晚上好。
Good evening.
这是你的房子吗?
Is this your house?
是的,它是。
Yes, it is.
我叫泽德。
My name is Zed.
很高兴见到你――
I'm glad to meet you--
非常高兴。
very glad.
我刚刚告诉他我飞船失事。
I was just telling him I was in a shipwreck.
我知道。
I know.
你知道?
You know?
怎么知道的?
How?
达莉亚！
TISA: Daria!
我以为我失去你了!
I thought I'd lost you!
没这样走运。
No such luck.
我猜我们仍然无法摆脱彼此。
I guess we're still stuck with each other.
我好怕你没成功。
I was afraid you didn't make it.
我深有感触。
I know the feeling.
你觉得我的新衣服怎么样?
How do you like my new outfit?
我们的东道主似乎什么都准备好了。
Our host seems to be ready for anything.
他对我当时的穿着不予置评。
He didn't say a word about the way I was dressed.
他一定觉得我有点衣衫褴褛
It must have occurred to him I was a shade
对于拥有一艘星际飞船。
shabby to own a starship.
嗯，我自己也不算时尚巅峰。
Well, I'm not exactly the height of fashion myself.
你提了不对劲的着陆坐标吗?
Have you mentioned the off-beam landing coordinates?
时机还没到。
The opportunity hasn't exactly presented itself.
我不想问太多问题，
I didn't want to start asking too many questions,
因为我不想回答任何问题。
because I didn't want to start answering any.
瓦克会带你去客房。
Vak will show you to a guestroom.
你必须马上脱掉那些衣服。
You must get out of those clothes at once.
于我心有戚戚焉。
They look just about the way I feel.
瓦克会给你找别的衣服。
Vak will find you others.
我们为这种紧急情况做了准备。
We're prepared for such emergencies.
晚餐马上就上。
Dinner will be served shortly.
你来的时候，我和我的客人们正要吃饭。
My guests and I were about to dine when you arrived.
我们会等你的。
We'll wait for you.
客人们?
Guests?
是的。
Yes.
还有另一艘失事船只的幸存者
There are survivors of another wreck
呆在这房子里。
staying here in the house.
另一艘失事船只?
Another wreck?
不幸的是，这个区域的太空航线
Unfortunately, the space lanes in this sector
是极其危险的。
are extremely dangerous.
这个我们以后再谈。
But we can talk about that later.
不要等我。
Don't wait for me.
我得花点时间梳洗打扮。
It'll take me a while to get myself cleaned up.
总之，失事让我还是有点惊魂未定。
And anyway, I'm still a little shook up from the crash.
我理解。
I understand.
也许你以后会加入我们。瓦克。
Perhaps you will join us later. Vak.
- 怎么了? - 没。
- Is anything wrong? - No.
没，没什么。
No, nothing.
给你衣服。
Here are your clothes.
告诉我，为什么窗户上有栅栏?
Tell me, why are there bars on these windows?
这曾经是一座古老的堡垒。
This was once an old fortress.
它由太空海盗建造，最后
It was built by space pirates, and eventually
在很久之前遗弃。
abandoned long ago.
现在栅栏把丛林的危险挡在外面。
Now the bars keep the dangers of the jungle out.
你搜过海岸了吗?
Have you searched the shore?
还有其他人吗?
Were there any others?
进来。
[KNOCKING] - Come in.
你美貌夺目。
You look breathtaking.
衣服非常适合你。
Fits you like a glove.
你从哪儿得来的衣服?
Where did you get it?
城堡以前房客们众多遗留物之一。
One of the many leftovers from the castle's previous tenants.
海盗掠夺品?
Pirate plunder?
瓦克一定告诉你此地历史一二了?
Vak must have been telling you some of our local history?
没我想知道的多。
Not as much as I'd like to know.
我们吃完晚餐了。
We finished dinner.
你的朋友蒂莎一直在询问你。
Your friend, Tisa, has been asking about you.
我现在精神好多了，谢谢。
I'm a bit more refreshed now, thanks.
我几乎恢复了正常。
I feel almost myself again.
那我们下去和其他人会合吧。
Then let's go down and join the others.
你需要的是一些刺激，
What you need is some stimulation,
一些有趣的同伴。
some interesting company.
两者我可以向你保证。
I can promise you both.
达莉亚，这是希拉，还有她的弟弟瑞克。
Daria, this is Shela, and her brother, Rik.
我耳闻了关于你的很多话。
I've heard a lot about you.
我希望没什么好话。
Nothing good, I hope.
蒂莎没有说其它的话。
SHELA: Tisa hasn't spoken of anything else.
你肯定是淑女报仇十年不晚。
It sure took you long enough to make it down.
你值得等待。
You're worth waiting for.
很荣幸两位美女
This is a pleasure-- two beautiful women
同一天到达。
arriving the same day.
直到美女你们出现，我才开始
Until you girls turned up, I was beginning to get
眼前一亮――
just a shade stir crazy--
10天只有丛林和海洋。
10 days of nothing but jungle and ocean.
瑞克对我的小岛一点也不感兴趣。
Rik is less than thrilled by my little island.
那为什么逗留?
Well, then why stay?
这不是我的主意。
It's not my idea.
只有一艘小艇，而且正在修理中。
There's only one launch, and that's being worked on.
我想你们得耐心稍等
Guess you'll have to be patient for a little while
更久。
longer.
如果我是你，我不会抱怨。
Well, I wouldn't complain if I were you.
我觉得我现在活在借来的光阴里。
I feel like I'm living on borrowed time right now.
我真的很高兴来到这里。
I'm just glad to be here.
宾至如归的舒适体验
All the comforts of home in the most
在银河系最遥远的角落。
remote corner of the galaxy.
太遥远了。
Too remote.
当然，这对你来说很完美，泽德。
Of course, it's perfect for you, Zed.
你可以随心所欲打猎。
You can go hunting if you want.
打猎?
Hunting?
在这里?
Here?
他白天睡觉，晚上打猎。
He sleeps all day and hunts all night.
我打赌他对你做同样的事。
Bet he has you doing the same thing.
你称这种对狩猎的痴迷为娱乐，
This obsession with hunting you call sport,
是不是有点矛盾?
isn't it just a little inconsistent?
为生存杀戮的丛林野兽
A beast in the jungle killing merely for his existence
被称为野蛮。
is called savage.
为娱乐杀戮的人被称为文明。
The man killing just for sport is called civilized.
这不是有点矛盾吗?
Isn't that a bit contradictory?
你凭什么认为它不是娱乐
What makes you think it isn't just
对动物来说和人一样是娱乐?
as much sport for the animal as it is for the man?
以这个家伙为例。
Take that fellow right there, for instance.
他从来没有逃不掉的时候。
There was never a time when he couldn't have gotten away.
但是他不想。
But he didn't want to.
他对狩猎我产生兴趣。
He got interested in hunting me.
他不恨我跟踪他
He didn't hate me for stalking him
就像我不恨他试图攻击我一样。
any more than I hated him for trying to charge me.
事实上，我们惺惺相惜。
Matter of fact, we admired each other.
也许。
Perhaps.
但是你愿意和他交换位置吗?
But would you change places with him?
不是现在。
Not now.
不要回避这个问题。
Don't evade the issue.
这游戏会有同样多的娱乐吗
Would there be as much sport in the game
如果你是猎物，而不是猎人?
if you were the prey, instead of the hunter?
这是我永远不必做出决定的事情。
That is something I will never have to decide.
这个宇宙被分为两类人
This universe is divided into two types of people--
猎人和猎物。
the hunter and the hunted.
你想去打猎吗?
You want to go hunting?
我们走。
Let's go.
我们开一个盛大派对，喝得酩酊大醉，
We'll have a big party, get totally blitzed,
然后扫射激光
and spray laser bolts--
覆盖丛林。
--all over the jungle.
十足文明的观点。
Completely civilized point of view.
文明?
SHELA: Civilized?
是的。
Yes.
瑞克带刺的话语就像狩猎的前奏。
Rik talks of stimulants as a prelude to the hunt.
就像早餐前喝鸡尾酒?
Cocktails before breakfast?
我们野蛮人知道，只在追逐之后喝
We barbarians know that it is only after the chase
男人满足之后。
that man indulges.
你知道阿特里克酋长的说法吗?
You know the saying of the Alteric chieftains?
先猎敌人，再猎女人。
Hunt first the enemy, then the woman.
这是每个地方野蛮人的想法。
That's the savage's idea everywhere.
这是自然的本能。
It's the natural instinct.
热血奔涌来自杀戮
Blood rushes from the kill.
一个激情澎湃，然后另一个激情消灭，然后爱。
One passion builds, then another kill, then love.
当你懂了这一点，你就懂了极乐。
And when you know that, then you know ecstasy.
原谅我。
Forgive me.
当我开始谈论狩猎时，
When I start talking about hunting,
我变得视而不见一切，
I become oblivious to everything,
即使是漂亮的女人。
even beautiful women.
你愿意为我们演奏吗?
Will you play for us?
泽德在这方面很有造诣
Zed's quite accomplished on this rather
他独特的乐器。
unique instrument of his.
这是全息琴弦
It's a holographic [INAUDIBLE]..
它就是将触碰改造成光声模式，
It simply transforms touch into patterns of light and sound,
我在这方面还不是很有造诣。
and I'm really not all that accomplished at it.
他太棒了。
SHELA: He's fantastic.
你们应该看看他能演奏出什么。
You should see what he can make it do.
如果你们确定你们听得下去的话。
Well, if you're sure that you can stand it.
我想透透气。
I could use some air.
你能赏脸陪我去吗?
Would you be gracious enough to accompany me?
我们的东道主的确是个不寻常的人物。
Our host certainly is an unusual character.
恐怖这个词更好。
RIK: Frightening is a better word.
不要信任他。
Don't trust him.
你为什么这么说?
What makes you say that?
我不像看起来那么醉。
I'm not as loaded as I seem.
这地方有不祥的事情在发生。
There's something sinister going on in this place.
我们都是这里的囚犯。
We're all prisoners here.
他的飞船没有任何问题。
There's nothing wrong with his spacecraft.
他谎称需要修理。
He lied about it needing repairs.
机器人在与补给船
The android makes a rendezvous with the supply
定期会合。
ship at regular intervals.
嗯，也许他喜欢你们的陪伴。
Well, perhaps he enjoys your company.
一周前我们有四个人。
There were four of us a week ago.
其他人消失了。
The others have disappeared.
一天晚饭后，他把我们的飞行员带进战利品室。
One night after dinner, he took our pilot into the trophy room.
锁着的门?
The locked door?
是的。
Yes.
昨晚他带走了我们的领航员。
Last night he took our navigator.
从那以后我们就没看见他。
We haven't seen him since.
你问过他他们的情况吗?
Have you asked him about them?
他说他们去打猎了。
He says they've gone hunting.
有多少机器人?
How many androids are there?
两个。
Two.
那边的瓦克照看房子。
Vak over there looks after the house.
克雷尔负责巡逻海滩和丛林。
Krel patrols the beaches and the jungle.
我们每时每刻都被监视着，不分昼夜。
We're watched every moment, night and day.
小心。
Be careful.
他在看着我们。
He's looking at us.
你不想再演奏吗?
SHELA: Won't you play some more?
你们一定累了。
You must be tired.
毕竟，是午夜了。
After all, it is midnight.
你们都该上床睡觉了。
It's time for all of you to turn in.
瓦克。
Vak.
每天晚上他打发我们上床睡觉
Every night, he packs us off to bed,
像对待坏小孩一样。
like bad, little children.
哦，我的亲爱的
ZED: Aw, my dear--
迷人的孩子们。
charming children.
这是迷人的一晚。
It's been a fascinating evening.
谁想睡觉?
Who wants to go to bed?
你答应过带我去战利品室的。
You promised to show me the trophy room.
是的，我答应了，但不是现在――以后。
Yes, I did, but not now-- later.
晚安。
Good night.
能被你营救我很高兴。
It's been a pleasure being rescued by you.
晚安。
Good night.
我害怕发出声音。
I was afraid to make a noise.
为什么?
Why?
我姐姐不在她的房间。
My sister's not in her room.
这很糟吗?
Is that so bad?
在这个地方很糟。
It is in this place.
我很担心。
I'm worried.
我是说，泽德在计划着什么事，
I mean, Zed's planning something, something
谋害希拉和我。
involving Shela and me.
你今晚喝得太多了。
You got pretty loaded tonight.
也许你只是在头脑中夸大了这一切。
Maybe you're just exaggerating all this in your mind.
我只是假装喝高了。
I was only pretending to be high.
为什么?
Why?
因为如果我保持清醒，我可能就是泽德的下一个牺牲品。
Because if I stay sober, I'm likely to be Zed's next victim.
你觉得她去哪了?
Where do you think she's gone?
其他人去哪了?
Where do the others go?
楼下的那扇门。
That door downstairs.
你吓死我了。
You scared me half out of my wits.
你在这下面干什么?
What are you doing down here?
总得有人去弄清楚这是什么地方。
Somebody had to find out what's in this place.
泽德和他的机器人离开后，我搜查了他的房间
After Zed and his boys left, I searched his room
找到了这把复制的钥匙。
and found this duplicate key.
你看到墙上的东西了吗?
Did you see what's on those walls?
是的。
Yeah.
这就是他对我们所有人的计划。
That's what he's planning for all of us.
这条走廊通向哪里?
Where does that corridor lead to?
他在后面藏了一艘逃生艇。
He's got an escape launch stashed back there.
这是我们离开这里的门票。
That's our ticket out of here.
不能不带上希拉。
Not without Shela.
对，但她在哪?
Yeah, but where is she?
- 下面有什么? - 我不知道。
- And down there? - I don't know.
我还没机会看。
I haven't had a chance to look.
一定有办法出去。
There must be some way out of here.
我们会找到答案。
We'll find out.
希拉仍然不见踪影。
Shela's still gone.
他们带的那个袋子里装的是什么?
What was in that sack they were carrying?
我们不妨面对事实:我们在跟疯子打交道。
We may as well face the fact we're dealing with a maniac.
我们只有一次机会赢那样的男人。
We've only one chance with a man like that.
我们得先下手为强。
We've got to get the jump on him.
他的激光枪放在哪里?
Where does he keep his laser guns?
你听他说了他用弓箭打猎。
You heard what he said about hunting with bow and arrow.
如果他有激光步枪，他一定
If he has any laser rifles, he must keep
把步枪封存在某处。
them locked up here somewhere.
至少我们知道他的船在哪里。
At least we know where he keeps his ship.
是的，但是你不能从外面到达飞船发射台。
Yes, but you can't get to the launch pad from outside.
我试过了。
I've tried.
这里没有栅栏。
There are no bars here.
我想知道为什么。
I wonder why.
这之前是泽德的房间。
It was Zed's room.
他把它给了希拉。
He gave it to Shela.
他很慷慨，但我们很幸运。
Generous of him, but lucky for us.
- 我们得找到她。- 我们会的。
- We have to find her. - We will.
我要搜查城堡。
I'm going to search the castle.
你只会被抓住，让泽德发现我们在对付他。
You'll only get caught and tip Zed off we're onto him.
离天亮还有几个小时
We've still got several hours before dawn,
我们必须利用这些时间。
and we have to use them to advantage.
你有刀吗?
Have you got a knife?
只有这个。
Only this.
这就够了。
It'll have to do.
泽德在这里忙的时候，你和我
While Zed is occupied here, you and I
在丛林里设陷阱
will set traps in the jungle.
如果他今晚又出去打猎，争取给我们发信号
If he leaves to go hunting again tonight, signal us if you can,
并努力找到希拉。
and try to find Shela.
泽德认为他把我们困住了。
Zed thinks he has us cornered.
但他可能会发现自己被困的感觉。
But he may find out how it feels to be trapped himself.
解决了他，机器人可能不会
With him out of the way, the androids might not
太难对付。
be too hard to handle.
如果他们检查我们的房间呢?
What if they check our rooms?
我们必须冒这个险。
It's a chance we'll have to take.
祝我们好运吧。
Wish us luck.
我们需要运气。
We'll need it.
快点回来。
Hurry back.
如果你们俩在外面被杀了
If you two get yourselves killed out there,
你们有我报仇。
you'll have me to answer to.
把你的手拿开。
Take your hands off me.
如果你不放我走，我弟弟会杀了你。
If you don't let me go, my brother will kill you.
我就希望这会煽起他仇恨的火焰――
I only hope that this will fan the flames of his hate--
可能会激励他采取行动。
might inspire him to action.
否则，我担心他会让我
Otherwise, I fear that he's going to provide
很少或没有挑战。
little or no challenge.
这很好。
That's good.
将会很好玩。
This will be fun.
你认为这个陷阱可靠吗?
Do you think the snare will hold?
听。
Listen.
你听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
是的。
Yeah.
如果泽德或他的机器人现在偶然发现这个陷阱，
If Zed or his droids stumble across this trap now,
我们完蛋。
we're sunk.
他朝这边来了。
He's coming this way.
那是什么?
What was that?
它不是泽德。
It wasn't Zed.
那东西看起来像是某种突变体。
That thing looked like some kind of mutant.
我觉得这丛林里还有更多古怪
Something tells me there's more in this jungle
比看到的要多。
than meets the eye.
你注意到小路上那棵倒下的树了吗?
Did you notice that fallen tree back there on the path?
很难错过，我们从下面走过。
Hard to miss. We walked under it.
如果我们砍掉支撑树枝，设置绊索藤蔓，
If we cut away the supporting branches or rig a trip vine,
这将是一个完美的陷阱。
it would make a perfect deadfall.
希望我们在黎明前还有足够的时间。
Hope we've got enough time left before dawn.
让我们做做看。
Let's find out.
如果有一把像样的刀，只需要一半的时间。
It would have taken half as long with a decent knife.
这个绊索有多敏感?
How sensitive is this trip wire?
轻轻碰一下藤蔓，这红木
The slightest touch on that vine and the mahogany log
会轰然倒塌，压碎它下面的任何东西。
comes crashing down, crushing anything beneath it.
那我们的赌注就全押在泽德是下一个
Then our whole bet rides on Zed being the next living
走上这条路的活物。
creature down this path.
我们别无选择，只能再次赌运气。
Just another chance we've got no choice but to take.
你知道吗，你不是唯一之前感觉
You know, you aren't the only one under the impression
泽德是这个星球上唯一居民的人。
that Zed was the sole inhabitant of this planet.
最近几小时显示情况不同。
The last few hours tell a different story.
我想知道还有什么生物在走路，在爬行，
I wonder what else is walking, crawling,
或者在外面滑行。
or slithering around out there.
时间会告诉我们。
Time will tell.
我们现在能做的就这了。
This is all we can do for now.
让我们回去。
Let's head back.
克雷尔，恐怕我们需要约束一下希拉。
Krel, I'm afraid we need to keep Shela under restraint.
如果她醒了，她可能会惊动我们的其他访客，
If she awakens, she is likely to alarm our other visitors,
除非我们让她舒服待在这里。
unless we keep her comfortable here.
太阳已经升起来了。
The sun is up already.
我们还有很长的路要走。
We've still got a ways to go yet.
这比我想的要长。
This is taking longer than I thought.
昨晚好像没这么远，即使是摸黑走。
It didn't seem this far last night, even in the dark.
不久我们就会被想念。
It won't be long before we're missed.
来吧。
Come on.
瓦克，检查楼上的房间。
Vak, check the upstairs rooms.
确保我们所有的客人都安全地睡在床上。
Make sure all of our guests are safely in their beds.
多么美好的一天。
What a delicious day it is.
早上游泳再合适不过了。
It's just perfect for a morning swim.
你不陪我一起去吗?
Won't you come with me?
泽德说丛林里充满了危险。
Zed says the jungle is just full of danger.
我会觉得安全好多，有像你这样又大又壮的机器人
I'd feel a whole lot safer with a big, strong android like you
来保护我。
along to protect me.
当然，我没有泳衣。
Of course, I haven't got a swimsuit.
但我相信你不会介意的。
But I'm sure you won't mind.
我需要检查楼上的客房。
I need to check the guest rooms upstairs.
何苦呢?
Why bother?
每个人都还在睡觉。
Everyone's still asleep.
我是唯一一个精力无处发泄的人
I'm the only one who's bright-eyed and bushy-tailed
今天早上。
this morning.
来吧。
Come on.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
我有命令。
I have my orders.
好吧，如果你现在不来，我就一个人去。
Well, if you're not coming now, I'm going alone.
克雷尔，该去海滩巡逻了。
Krel, it's time to patrol the beaches again.
通知我，如果你发现什么异常情况
Send word to me if you spot anything unusual
或者我可能感兴趣的事，但只限于
or I might be interested in, but only
值得叫醒我的情况。
if it's worth waking me for.
你确定这条路是对的吗?
Are you sure this is the right trail?
我什么都不确定了。
I'm not sure about anything anymore.
就在这里。
Just about here.
现在，你就在这里等着，我去泡个澡。
Now, you just wait right here while I go take a dip.
你在这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
看她。
Watching her.
主人命令你检查楼上的房间。
The master ordered you to check the upstairs rooms.
家里一切正常。
Everything at the house is in order.
你亲眼看到了吗?
Did you see for yourself?
嗯,哦,不。
Well, uh, no.
我想你应该守着房子。
I think you should be guarding the house.
你想?
You think?
你从来没有想过你的整个存在意义。
You've never thought for your entire existence.
你在骂人。
You are insulting.
你说得对。
You are correct.
我们怎么从他们身边溜过去?
How are we going to sneak past them?
他们就在我们下面。
They're right below us.
希望我能引起蒂莎的注意
Let's hope I can get Tisa's attention
在铬合金机器人发现我们之前。
before the chrome domes spot us.
蒂莎！蒂莎！
(WHISPERING) Tisa! Tisa!
蒂莎！
Tisa!
你应该回屋去。
You should return to the house.
我不听你的命令。
I don't take orders from you.
瓦克，有什么不对吗?
Vak, is anything wrong?
我希望我没有造成任何麻烦。
I hope I haven't caused any trouble.
没。没有问题。
No. No problem.
能把我的毛巾给我吗?
Could you bring me my towel?
你不在主人会不高兴的。
The master will not be pleased with your absence.
你让我不高兴，我不理你。
You displease me, and I ignore you.
瓦克，别管毛巾了。
Vak, never mind the towel.
我要再呆一会儿。
I'm going to stay in a little longer.
我要通知主人。
I'm going to inform the master.
打小报告的!
Tattletale!
脱衣服。
Take off your shirt.
快快快!
Go, go, go!
必须让人相信。
This has to be convincing.
我信了。
I'm convinced.
哦。
Aw.
哦。呃。
Oh. Uh.
男人和女人――一个伟大的概念。
Man and woman-- a great concept.
我爱它。
I love it.
直到现在我才知道我有多想做爱。
I never knew how much I missed making love until just now.
至少可以说，我最近饱受磨难。
I've been through a lot lately, to say the least.
你让我觉得自己又活过来了。
You made me feel alive again.
我知道我想要什么。
I know what I want.
我知道我在为什么战斗。
I know what it is I'm fighting for.
谢谢。
Thanks.
你不用谢我。
You don't have to thank me.
这是我的荣幸。
It was my pleasure.
如果我今天死了，我也毫无怨言。
If I die today, I wouldn't complain.
现在，这一刻，我一定是最快乐的男人
Right now, this moment, I have to be the happiest guy
在宇宙中。
in the universe.
毫无疑问，你一直想知道你姐姐的情况。
No doubt you've been wondering about your sister.
她是我的囚犯。
She's my prisoner.
给你机会。
Here's your chance.
枪上有定时器，10分钟内不会激活。
Timer on the gun won't activate for 10 minutes.
我允许你先走一步。
I'm allowing you that much head start.
如果你能一直躲到天亮，或者杀了我，
If you can elude me until dawn, or kill me,
那么你赢得了你的自由，和她的自由。
then you've won your freedom, and hers.
你会后悔的。
You'll regret this.
这不是一个特别新颖的回应，
Not a particularly original response,
但我相信它是真诚的
but I am sure that it is a sincere
表达了你的感受。
expression of your feelings.
我建议你快点。
I suggest you hurry.
你的时间不多了。
Your time is running out.
哦。
Aw.
迷药很快就会失效。
The drug will wear off quickly.
我不想以任何方式影响你们的活泼性。
I wouldn't want to compromise your alertness in any way.
那就违背了我的初衷。
That would defeat my entire purpose.
你是个没人性的恶魔。
You're an inhuman fiend.
没有必要把那给她看。
There was no need to show that to her.
我们都有不同的需求
We all have different needs--
我们中的一些人，非常不同。
some of us, very different.
我的刺激体验，非常特别――
Experiences which stimulate me, singularly specific--
我有自己独特的哲学，
I have my own special philosophy,
符合我独特的生活方式。
consistent with my unique lifestyle.
我总觉得生命最美好的时光离死亡最近。
I've always felt that the best of life lies closest to death.
生活在边缘――
Living on the edge--
那里你找到生活的刺激。
that's where you find the thrill of life.
我完全不同意你的看法。
I couldn't agree with you less.
生命的美好在于尽可能远离死亡。
The best of life lies as far from death as possible.
最终，没有人能赢得生命的游戏。
In the end, no one wins the game of life.
是的。
Yes.
但我还是希望输得越慢越好。
But I prefer to lose as slowly as I can.
你有机会把你的哲学和我的哲学相比较
You'll have your chance to pit your philosophy against mine--
较量技巧一分高下
a contest of skills played on the chess
在我的私人星球棋盘上。
board of my private planet.
我打算狩猎你们。
I intend to hunt you.
你不是认真的吧。
You can't be serious.
你不会真要狩猎女人吧?
You're not going to hunt women, are you?
我总是发现这个物种的雌性
I've always found the female of the species
带来最大的挑战，
to be the greatest challenge, far
远比男性对手更诡计多端。
more crafty and cunning than their male counterparts.
她们狡猾，不可预测，充满惊喜
They're devious, unpredictable, full of surprises--
美妙的惊喜。
wonderful surprises.
我会尽量让你猜不透。
I'll do my best to keep you guessing.
我将同时释放你们三个。
I'm going to release the three of you simultaneously.
我将给你们猎刀，让你们先走一小时。
I'm going to give you hunting knives and an hour head start.
在我的岛的远端有一座寺庙
There's a temple on the far side of my island containing
存有高能激光武器。
high-powered laser weapons.
如果你们能成功走那么远，那些武器会给你们
If you can make it that far, those weapons will give you
更多的生机。
more than a fighting chance.
这是一张去寺庙的地图。
Here is a map with directions to the temple.
还有最后的床第请求吗?
Any last plea for compassion?
你不能这么做。
You can't do this.
生命太宝贵，不能为娱乐被屠宰。
Life is too precious to be killed for sport.
这是一个冰冷的宇宙。
It's a cold cosmos.
给你们尖牙利爪。
Here are your claws and fangs.
我希望你们三个提供给我
I expect the three of you to provide
非比寻常的挑战。
me with an unusual challenge.
我们将努力不辜负你的期望。
We'll try to live up to your expectations.
我会把自己限制在我最喜欢的轻武器上
I'm going to limit myself to my favorite light weapons--
手枪弩。
pistol crossbows.
你真慷慨，让这么多子。
Generous of you to handicap yourself so severely.
我想给你们一切打败我的机会。
ZED: I want to give you every opportunity to beat me.
这也激发了我的竞争本能。
Even that stimulates my competitive instincts.
我要好好享受这一切。
I am going to enjoy this.
我帮不上这个忙。
Not if I can help it.
我建议我们不要再浪费时间了。
I suggest we waste no more time.
良好的开端意味着一切。
A good head start is everything.
给一个忠告
One word of advice--
尽量不要在幽灵区迷路。
try not to get lost in the phantom zone.
我想把这把刀插进他的心脏。
SHELA: I want to bury this knife in his heart.
我要在这里等泽德，然后伏击他。
I'm going to wait for Zed right here and ambush him.
他绝不会想到。
He'd never expect it.
你绝不会知道怎么死的。
You'd never know what hit you.
我们唯一的希望就是团结一致。
Our only hope is to stick together.
单打独斗，他只要一次干掉我们一个人。
Alone, he'll only pick us off one at a time.
我们三个人人多力量大。
The three of us outnumber him.
陷阱就在前面。
The trap lies just ahead.
这个陷阱帮不上我们忙了。
This trap isn't going to do us any good.
至少我们不会在路上碰到他了。
At least we won't be running into him on the trail.
是啊，但他的伴侣可能不太高兴。
Yeah, but his mate might not be too happy about this.
让我看看那张地图。
Let me take a look at that map.
应该是这条路。
This should be the way.
你比我更需要丰胸。
You need this more than I do.
只要一碰隐藏的绊索藤蔓，
Just touch that hidden trip vine,
10吨重的树就压在你的身上。
and you have 10 tons of tree in your lap.
这是一个我宁愿避免的头痛。
That's one headache I'd rather avoid.
- 小心脚下! - 我会蹑手蹑脚。
- Watch your step! - I'll tiptoe.
看来我们已经走了很远了。
It seems as though we've come miles.
在这么稠密的丛林里一个小时走不了多远。
An hour doesn't take you far in jungle this dense.
泽德现在应该已经出发了。
Zed should be starting out about now.
他会很快追来。
He'll be coming fast.
让我看看地图，确定一下我们的方位。
Let me check the map and get our bearings.
它不在这里。
It's not here.
它一定是掉在路上了。
It must have fallen out somewhere along the path.
不奇怪它滑落了。
It's no wonder it slipped through.
我应该自己塞着它。
I should have held onto it myself.
- 我们一起回去找。- 不。
- Let's go back together. - No.
我丢的。
I lost it.
我去找。继续走。
I'll find it. Stick to the path.
我会赶上你们的。
I'll catch up with you.
当心陷阱。
Watch out for the deadfall.
这就像她要把自己碾碎一样。
It would be just like her to get herself crushed.
我累了。
I'm tired.
我受够了。
I'm sick of this.
我不想为我的生命而战了。
I don't want to have to fight for my life.
考虑另一选择。
Consider the alternative.
泽德的战利品室里的头颅看起来不太高兴。
Those heads in Zed's trophy room didn't look too happy to me.
我受够了这么害怕。
I am tired of being so scared.
瑞克的事我很同情。
I'm sorry about Rik.
我知道同情改变不了什么
I know sorry doesn't change anything,
但我还是想让你知道我的感觉。
but I want you to know how I feel, just the same.
谢谢。
Thanks.
突然之间，简单的人类温情意义重大。
Suddenly, simple human warmth means a lot.
在这一切发生之前，我从不知道我如此需要朋友。
I never knew I needed friends so much before all this happened.
我们已经侦查得够远了
Well, we've scouted far enough ahead to see
明白了这条路的走向。
what this trail has to offer.
我们回去在峡谷边等蒂莎怎么样?
What do you say we go back and wait for Tisa by the chasm?
半路接应她?
Meet her halfway?
我不想让泽德追上她时我们不在她身边
I don't want Zed catching up with her without us
支援她。
there to back her up.
如果泽德发现了蒂莎，她没机会生还。
If Zed spots Tisa, she won't stand a chance.
我们得把他引开。
We've got to flush him out.
但如何?
But how?
只有一个办法。
There's only one way.
她不该这样惨死。
She deserved better than this.
她为我牺牲了自己。
She sacrificed herself for me.
命运女神肯定在胡乱织锦。
Fate certainly weaves a twisted tapestry.
如果奴隶贩子们从我们身边经过就好了。
If only the slavers had passed us by.
如果，如果，我受够了如果。
If, if-- I'm sick of ifs.
如果生活不是那么残酷，一切多美好。
If life wasn't so cruel, everything would be beautiful.
生活才不在乎。
Life doesn't care.
看看这片丛林。
Look at this jungle.
它里面的一切生物通过杀死别的生物而生存
Everything in it survives by killing something else--
不是出于选择，而是出于环境。
not by choice, just by circumstance.
泽德杀戮是出于选择。
Zed kills by choice.
我也选定了。
So will I.
我们要回去结果泽德吗?
Do we go back and finish Zed off?
用这些吗?
With these?
那尖桩可能会让他慢下来，但阻止不了他。
That spike may slow him down, but it won't stop him.
他拿着那些小弩太难对付了。
He's too hot with those little crossbows to suit me.
我们就是活靶子。
And we make such attractive targets.
我渴望得到一些真正的武器。
I'm itching to get my hands on some serious weapons.
能保证这寺庙存在吗?
Is there any guarantee this temple even exists?
那我们又损失什么呢?
Well, what have we got to lose?
不用回答这问题。
Don't answer that.
你曾梦想过生活会变成这样吗?
Did you ever dream life would turn out like this?
一百万年也想不到。
Never in a million years.
一百万年。
A million years.
如果我们能活到天亮，我就谢天谢地了。
I'll be thankful if we survive until dawn.
这一定是扳机石，但什么也没发生。
This must be the keystone, but nothing's happening.
如果这机械装置不再运转了呢?
What if this mechanism no longer operates?
从生到死是人所能及。
From life to death is the reach of man.
如果这个面板代表死亡，那么我猜
If this panel represents death, then my guess
相邻的面板代表生命。
is the adjacent panel represents life.
现在，蒂莎，当我说开始时，我们推两个面板
Now, Tisa, when I say go, we push both panels
同时，好吗？开始！
at the same time, OK? Go!
这一定是泽德警告过我们的幽灵区。
This must be the phantom zone Zed warned us about.
他真体贴，没有说
Considerate of him not to mention
幽灵区包围着武器。
it surrounds the weapons.
我有奇怪的感觉，时间和空间的正常规律
I have the strangest feeling the normal laws of time and space
不再适用。
no longer apply.
如果我们分开了――蒂莎?
If we get separated-- Tisa?
蒂莎?
[ECHOING] Tisa?
Tisa?
蒂莎?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我做过的噩梦都没有这么可怕。
I've had nightmares that weren't as scary as this.
不要碰它。
Don't touch it.
一开始我就是这样激活他的。
That's how I activated him in the first place.
他被激光打成筛子了。
He's ventilated with laser holes.
他现在是历史了。
He is history now.
历史总有办法重演。
History has a way of repeating itself.
哦,是吗?
Oh yeah?
这里有一些东西将帮助我们改变
Here are some things which will help us change
未来的进程。
the course of the future.
自助。
Help yourself.
我们还得想办法出去
We've still got to find a way out
在更多尖叫恶魔
of here before any more screaming demons
从雾中飞过来之前。
come flying through the fog.
我们什么也看不见。
We can't see a thing.
这意味着我们将不得不使用我们的其他感官――
Which means we'll have to use our other senses--
超声波定位。
supersonic psycussion.
怎么用?
What about it?
这就是答案。
That's the answer.
这武器发出致命的声波。
This emits deadly sonic shock waves.
如果我360度开火
If I fire in a 360-degree pattern--
没有回声的射击方向
The shot that doesn't echo back
就是通向外界的方向。
will be the direction of the opening to the outside.
完全正确。
Exactly.
让我们做它!
Let's do it!
你认为我们有机会吗?
Do you think we have a chance?
我知道我们有。
I know we do.
必须找到她。
Have to find her.
必须找到她。在哪里?
Have to find her. Where?
死亡总是令人难以置信――
Death is always incredible--
永远以为是别人，从没想到是自己。
always for others, never for ourselves.
这个的点火装置在哪里?
Where's the ignition on this one?
它用声音激活。
It's voice activated.
这对你来说应该不成问题。
That shouldn't be any problem for you.
幻影驱动已开。
Phantom drive is engaged.
引擎已热。
Engine's hot.
我们走!
Let's go!
右舵，左舵。
Right rudder, left rudder.
下降20度。
Descend 20 degrees.
减速。
Slow down.
我们要撞到那东西。
We're going to hit that thing.
拉起！拉起！
Pull up! Pull up!
你的驾驶谁教的?
Who taught you how to drive?
快带我们离开这里！快！
Get us out of here, fast!
我们有必要偷这么贵的船吗?
Did we have to steal such an expensive ship?
你知道造这些东西在厂里要花多少时间吗?
Do you know how much time these things spend in the shop?
那事情结束了。
That was close.
现在我们做什么?
Now what do we do?
我们的宇宙浩瀚无垠，充满了奇迹。
Our universe is vast, full of wonders.
我们将一起探索，发现陌生的新世界。
We'll explore, find strange, new worlds, together.